<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <bookinfo>
    <title>Mydigipass User's Guide</title>

    <author>
      <firstname>Daniel</firstname>

      <surname>Dimitrov</surname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname>compojoom.com</orgname>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <pubdate>23.06.2014</pubdate>

    <legalnotice>
      <para>Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
      document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version
      1.3 or any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with
      no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts. A
      copy of the license is included in the appendix entitled "The GNU Free
      Documentation License".</para>
    </legalnotice>

    <abstract>
      <para>This book covers the use of Mydigipass for Joomla package. It does
      not cover any other extension available on compojoom.com .</para>
    </abstract>
  </bookinfo>

  <article>
    <para><revhistory>
        <revision>
          <revnumber>MyDigipass 1.0 - Revision 0.1</revnumber>

          <date>23.06.2014</date>

          <author>
            <firstname>Daniel</firstname>

            <surname>Dimitrov</surname>
          </author>
        </revision>
      </revhistory></para>
  </article>

  <chapter>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <section>
      <title>Introducing Mydigipass</title>

      <para><ulink url="http://mydigipass.com">Mydigipass.com</ulink>™ is a
      security service aiming to protect your online identity. The service is
      developed by the VASCO® Data Security GmbH and through this
      documentation we will just call it Mydigipass API.</para>

      <para>The Mydigipass package distributed through compojoom.com is a
      collection of modules and plugins that makes integrating the mydigipass
      API with your Joomla! site a breeze.</para>

      <para>So what does mydigipass.com exactly do?</para>

      <para>On typical Joomla! site, users login with email addresses and
      static passwords: <emphasis>something they know</emphasis>. Two-factor
      authentication adds <emphasis>something they have</emphasis> to the
      authentication process. If you install and configure the mydigipass
      package on your Joomla site, users will securely login by generating a
      OTP (one time password) using their authenticator by scanning a QR code
      with their mobile devices, authenticating via the embedded DIGIPASS in
      Intel® IPT on their laptop, ob by using on of the digipass hardware
      tokens. The authenticator is <emphasis>what the user has </emphasis>and
      is the second authentication factor.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Installation and updates</title>

    <para>Installing Mydigipass is no different than installing any other
    Joomla!™ extension on your site. You can read the complete instructions
    for installing Joomla!™ extensions on the <ulink
    url="http://help.joomla.org/content/view/1476/235/">official help
    page</ulink> .Throughout this chapter we assume that you are familiar with
    these instructions and we will not duplicate them.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Getting the installation packages</title>

      <para>The mydigipass package is located under Downloads -&gt; Official
      releases -&gt; Mydigipass. The releases are listed with the newest
      release always on top. Once you click on the release number you'll see
      the available files for download.</para>

      <para>You can use the installation package to update from previous
      version as well; just install it, without uninstalling the old
      package.</para>

      <para><note>
          <para>The zip package includes all available modules and plugins.
          During the installation they will be installed automatically.</para>
        </note></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Installing a developer release</title>

      <para>In normal cases you won't have to install developer releases. You
      are advised to go to the download area and grab the normal package as
      described in the past chapter. However there are situations where things
      are not working - if we confirm the problem, we fix it and generally
      release a developer release to test the fix. We proceed the same way
      with new features - we add them and create a developer release for those
      of you who like to experiment with them before the official release gets
      published.</para>

      <para>To get the latest developer release navigate to Downloads -&gt;
      Developer Releases -&gt; Mydigipass. The latest release is always on
      top. Download the package and install it through the Joomla extension
      manager.</para>

      <important>
        <para>Please note: Having a backup is never a bad idea!</para>
      </important>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Updating to the latest version</title>

      <section>
        <title>Checking for the latest version and upgrading</title>

        <para>We use the standard Joomla update manager to notify you about
        updates. In your Joomla backend click on Extensions-&gt; Extension
        Manager -&gt; Update and click on Find updates.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Uninstall</title>

      <para>You can uninstall the Mydigipass package just as any other Joomla
      extension. Just navigate to Extensions -&gt; Extension Manager -&gt;
      Manage -&gt; search for Mydigipass (package), select it and click
      uninstall. The uninstall process will remove all installed plugins and
      modules as well.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Using Mydigipass for Joomla</title>

    <para>If you've installed the mydigipass plugin as described in the past
    chapter then we've installed the following plugins and modules on your
    Joomla website</para>

    <para><orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>System - Mydigipass</para>

          <para>This plugin handles the authentication against the mydigipass
          API and logs you into your Joomla site.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Mydigipass module</para>

          <para>This module shows a button for login or connecting in the
          frontend of your site</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Mydigipass admin module</para>

          <para>This module shows a login button on the administrator login in
          the backend.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>

    <para>For more information on the above plugins and modules look at the
    next chapters.</para>

    <section>
      <title>System - Mydigipass</title>

      <para>This plugin handles the authentication against the mydigipass API
      and logs the user into your Joomla site. You'll need to configure it in
      order for it to communicate properly with mydigipass API.</para>

      <para>The configuration options are as follow:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Client id</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the client id of your developer.mydigipass.com
            project.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Client secret</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the client secret code of your
            developer.mydigipass.com project.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Redirect URI</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Copy the URI provided on the right into the options of your
            developer.mydigipass.com application.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Sandbox mode</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>If in sandbox mode you can test the plugin and make sure
            that everything works as expected. If you are ready to go live,
            then you need to request API credentials from mydigipass. Look for
            the Go live button in your developer.mydigipass.com
            account.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Block standard login</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>This options determines whether we should block users from
            login in through the standard joomla login form if they have
            connected their accounts with mydigipass.com. If you set this
            option to yes, then once a user connects his account with
            mydigipass.com the only way he would be able to login on your site
            is through the mydigipass button. The standard login form won't
            work! This is part of the two-factor authentication. If a user has
            connected his profile with mydigipass, then he wants to use the
            added security benefit of mydigipass. So it doesn't make sense for
            him to still be able to login through the normal joomla
            login.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <important>
        <para>If you set the block standard login option to yes, you need to
        make sure that the mydigipass admin module is published in the
        backend. If it is not and your admin account has been connected with
        mydigipass.com you won't be able to login into your joomla
        backend.</para>
      </important>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Mydigipass module</title>

      <para>This module shows a "mydigipass.com secure login" button to
      non-logged in users. And "mydigipass.com connect" button to logged in
      users. If the user has already connected his profile you have the option
      to hide the module.</para>

      <para>Module options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Show label already connected</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Determines whether or not to show information to a user who
            has his account already connected with mydigipass.com</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Mydigipass admin module</title>

      <para>This module shows a "mydigipass.com secure login" in the
      administrator section of the website.</para>

      <note>
        <para>To make use of this function as administrator you have to
        connect your account through the frontend first.</para>
      </note>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>FAQ</title>

    <para/>

    <section>
      <title>I've enabled block standard login and now I can't login into my
      Joomla backend</title>

      <para>If you've enabled the block standard login option in the plugin
      settings, then people who have connected their accounts with
      mydigipass.com won't be ablet o use the standard joomla login. They
      would need to click on the mydigipass login button in order to login. If
      you are an administrator on the site and you've connected your profile
      with mydigipass.com you would need to use mydigipass.com in the joomla
      backend as well. If you have forgotten to publish the mydigipass admin
      module in your joomla backend you will no longer be able to login there.
      </para>

      <para>Don't panic! You will be able to login into the backend again, but
      you need to unlink your account and for this you'll need access to your
      database preferably through phpmyadmin. Once you are logged into your
      database navigate to the #__user_profiles table and look for the
      settings for your user id. If you don't know your user id, navigate to
      #__users and look for your username in there. The id column will give
      you an idea what your id number is. Once you have the id go back to the
      #__user_profiles table, find the records for your user_id and delete the
      uuid setting. Now you should be able to login again.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Where to go from here?</title>

    <para>If you encounter any problems or have feature suggestions don't
    hesitate to <ulink url="https://compojoom.com/about/contact-us">contact
    us</ulink>!</para>
  </chapter>
</book>
